I'm honored to introduce our next inductee into the International Hall of Fame,
Mayor Richard Ganim.
All who said that it couldn't be with us tonight.
If there is nothing in the world, could it start him from being here tonight
other than his illness?
It is a privilege to induct a person that I expect and I consider him a friend
and a mentor.
I'm pleased to share his outstanding accomplishments and achievements.
Richard Ganim was born in Cleveland to Joseph Anazah, who was created from
Tehran to the U.S. in the early 1900s,
the ninth child of 12 children.
Ethnic pride is important to the Ganim family. As an example, his parents
mandated their children to assist in chores
and maintenance at their church, St. Mary's, Mar a Main Catholic Church, which
is an area here.
Without our Monsignor with us, the pastor of our St. Mary Monsignor, Peter Perron,
thank you for being here.
Also, our church is hosting this year the National Convention of the L
was instrumental in purchasing and developing and expanding the parish, which
is now one of the largest parishes in the U.S.
He remains devoted to this tradition today with his continued involvement and
worship at St. Mary's and the other expanding parishes,
which are now located downtown and in the dependency area. He just purchased
another 26 acres a few years back in the dependency area.
When I think of Richard Ganim, I think of his family. He has a wife, Barry, who
has been married for 64 years,
has five children, 16 grandchildren and eight great grandchildren.
As a successful business person and family man, it was a tremendous honor to
the Lebanese and Middle Eastern communities.
One Richard was the first elected official in the state of Ohio of Lebanese Lisan.
In the city of Seven Hills, he was twice elected councilman, twice elected
finance director and served two terms as the mayor of Seven Hills.
And also with us tonight, our mayor of Seven Hills, Maya Dehapila, thank you
for being here tonight.
Richard, as he tried, motivated him to be one of the original founders,
president for many years of Gambia,
the female American
community when needed. He has given inspiration to many, as he was for myself.
The former superstar and behind the mold with Kenya.
Kenya grew to be the most respected and so lefted organization in Cleveland,
with a holy county and state of Ohio.
And it represents the views and concern of the more than 250,000 people of
Middle Eastern descent in this area.
Actually, Kenya was here celebrating our 20th anniversary. The Saturday, May 2nd,
and all of you are invited to attend.
Richard became the flagship of this community. He has been an inspiration to
them. He's been involved with many other charitable foundations, including the
Ryan Moha Foundation,
named after his grandson, who lost his life too early. The foundation for poor
youth activities through positive engagement.
Richard has shared many memorable reflections with myself and my family of what
it means to be a Vanina.
He has never been to Alabama, though he will never guess it.
When you speak with him, you will feel his warmth toward his parents' homeland
and the price of his heritage.
His stories are moving and his goal is our children will hold on their
traditions, faith and pride as he knows.
His happy pride does not match his pride of being an American. His contribution
to this country is unmatched as he serves in the armed forces,
as an army airborne as they are until the end of the World War II.
Richard is always the first to proudly explain his heritage and the essence of
being American to Americans.
His mission is to see all of us succeed and work together, cohesively, and be
proud of each other.
I want to take a special thanks to the greatly true and our community, thef
evenpeople.com, who are very lucky to have your equipment, always supporting
the ethnic communities,
excluding and sharing the greatness of our different cultures and neighborhoods.
Thank you, ma'am, the grandmothers.
[applause]